beuc.eu 2018-07-21

# Privacy Policy | www.beuc.eu

This privacy policy has been updated on 27 June 2018

## Privacy Policy

We strongly believe in your fundamental rights to privacy and data protection. We strictly limit the processing of your personal information to the minimum possible for the specific purposes described in this privacy policy and we try to use the services of only those companies that respect your privacy.

## Cookies

We use cookies on our website [www.beuc.eu](http://www.beuc.eu/). Cookies are text files containing a small amount of data which is sent to your computer when you visit our website. They involve the collection and storage of personal information.

We only install those cookies which are strictly necessary for the correct functioning of our website.

We use the services of the analytics company [Matomo](http://matomo.org/) (formerly known as Piwik) to analyse the use of our website and to monitor when, where and how people access information so that we can adapt the site to better suit our users' needs and measure its performance. We have chosen Matomo because it fully respects your privacy. For example, it anonymises your IP by removing its last octet, so we will never know your full IP address.

### Cookies we use

  1. Context_breakpoint cookie: This cookie checks if the user is visiting from a mobile device or not, to render the site accordingly.
  2. Javascript cookie: This cookie checks if there is Javascript or not. If not, the visitor sees a less interactive version of the site.
  3. Session cookie: This cookie remembers the information you have been searching for on our website. It is deleted as soon as you close your browser.
  4. Cookie banner: This cookie is used to remember your choice when you land on our website for the first time and you decide whether or not to accept our cookies.
  5. Analytics cookie: We use Matomo (formerly known as Piwik) to monitor and analyse traffic on our website. It will collect usage statistics such as the number of page visits, documents downloaded etc. and provides us with aggregate numbers. Any IP addresses collected have the last octet removed. This cookie is very important for us to evaluate the correct functioning of our website and the impact of our activities. Further information on how Matomo respects your privacy can be found [here](https://matomo.org/gdpr/).
  6. Dailymotion cookie: We use the video sharing platform Dailymotion which requires the installation of their cookie to embed videos into our website. To find out more about the privacy policy of Dailymotion please click [here](https://www.dailymotion.com/legal/privacy?localization=be).
  7. Social media: We have tried to avoid any third party social media plugins to the extent possible. The only social plugging that can be found on our site is from Twitter and is used to enable the Twitter wall in our homepage. Our website offers also the possibility to share content via the most common social media platforms. When you decide to share a piece of content through one of those platforms, our website will link you to that platform. Be advised that when you do this you are bound by the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policy of the social media platform in question.

## Embedded content

Fonts: The fonts used for the content of the subpage [www.ThePriceofBadAdvice.eu](http://www.thepriceofbadadvice.eu/) come from Font Awesome - you can find their privacy policy [here ](https://fontawesome.com/privacy)\- and Google Fonts. We unfortunately have no control over the data that Google might collect through the domains fonts.googleapis.com and fonts.gstatic.com, which are governed by Google's [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). We recommend users to install privacy protection tools such as [Privacy Badger](https://www.eff.org/privacybadger) in order to be protected from any possible tracking carried out by Google through these domains.

## Job Vacancies

The personal data we collect during hiring processes is only used for the purposes of carrying out the selection process and is deleted once the process has ended. For shortlisted candidates, we routinely ask for their consent to keep their information for 6 months after the end of the selection process, in case other vacancies that could fit their profile open up.

## Your data protection rights

  * Right of access – You have the right to have access to the personal data we hold about you and to obtain a copy.
  * Right to rectification – You have the right to obtain the rectification of the personal data we have about you if it is inaccurate.
  * Right to erasure – You have the right to obtain the erasure of the personal data we have about you.
  * Right to restriction of processing – If you believe the personal data we have is not accurate or that we are not using it lawfully but do not want to simply ask that we delete it straight away, you have the right to ask us to stop using the data while we sort out the problems.
  * Right to data portability – You have the right to receive the data that you have provided in a commonly used format, so you can take it somewhere else if you wish.
  * Right to object – You have the right to object to the use of your data for marketing purposes at any time. Note that we do not use your data for marketing in any way!
  * Right to lodge a complaint – If you believe your rights are not being respected and your data is being used unlawfully, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your national Data Protection Authority. You can find the contact details of all national data protection authorities [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

## Updates & contact

### Changes to our Policy

It might happen that we have to change our Privacy Policy, for instance to comply with new legal requirements. If we make any changes to our policy, we will make this information publicly available on our website; the date and nature of the change will also be clearly indicated.

### How to contact us

If you have any requests, questions, complaints or queries with regards to how we use your information, we encourage you to contact us and we will do our best to resolve it.

#### Our contact details:

BEUC – The European Consumer Organisation  
Rue d’Arlon 80  
B-1040 Brussels  
Belgium

Email: [privacy@beuc.eu](mailto:privacy@beuc.eu)

Tel: +32 2 743 15 90  
Fax: +32 2 740 28 02
